Nathaniel Cain

nathanielcain.com

■ nathaniel2897@gmail.com

github.com/yunglaundromat

in linkedin.com/in/nathaniel-cain

EDUCATION

City College of New York

Earned credits towards Bachelor's Degree in Political Science September 2015 - June 2017

Bard College

Associate of Arts
Graduated June 2015

ABOUT ME

Full stack web developer with a passion for urban exploration, political science, rock climbing and cartography. With over 2 years of experience in Rails, Javascript, and React.js and a background in sales and team leadership, I thrive in an environment of collaboration and respect.

EXPERIENCE

Infosys

Operations Associate

March 2020 – present Remote

- Trained on a variety of technologies, including basic Java, Selenium, and Unix scripting.
- Interviewed directly with clients of large-scale applications utilizing Selenium with Java.

Flatiron School

February 2019 – June 2019 New York, NY

Full Stack Web Developer

- Full stack developer, gaining fluency in vanilla Ruby and Javascript, as well as React.js, Redux, and Ruby on Rails.
- Achieved proficiency in Chrome DevTools, Materialize, Semantic UI, Authentication using JWT, SQLite, and PostgreSQL.
- CryptoTrader: Cryptocurrency purchasing simulator that reflects real-time values of cryptocurrency. Uses React.js client-side and Ruby on Rails server-side. Fetches data to the frontend using Coinranking API, which updates every few minutes with new data on coin values. Persists purchase data to the local backend.
- BikeShare International: Comprehensive app to assist users looking to find bike share stations in cities across the world.
 Fetches data of every bike share system internationally from City Bikes API, giving users information on station location, free spaces, and bikes available. Persists "favorited" systems by user to server-side using Rails.

Brooklyn Boulders

Sep 2016 – Aug 2018 Brooklyn, NY

Community Specialist

Grill Chef Lead

- Greeted and assisted community members in front-desk check-in and Facility Orientations in a busy, fast-paced climbing gym.
- Consistently met and exceeded weekly and monthly sales goals, and completed thorough training sessions on crucial customer service skills.

Brooklyn Farmacy & Soda Fountain

Apr 2015 – Sep 2016 Brooklyn, NY

 Worked a variety of positions, including front-of-counter, server, and host, while contributing to a highly-profitable, fast-paced restaurant environment.